Guide to the Flora Stieglitz Straus Collection of Stieglitz Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Flora Stieglitz Straus collection of Stieglitz family papers
1860-1999
YCAL MSS 89
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
5.3
(18 boxes)
The Flora Stieglitz Straus Collection of Stieglitz Family Papers consists of letters, photographs, printed materials, journals, and a scrapbook documenting the lives of Alfred Stieglitz's extended family. Included in the first series, Stieglitz Family Papers, are letters between family members, a draft of an autobiography by Edward J. Stieglitz, and biographical information about Julius Stieglitz. Series II, Alfred Stieglitz and Georgia O'Keeffe, contains a number of letters from Stieglitz and Georgia O'Keeffe to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson and Donald Douglas Davidson, and to Flora Stieglitz Straus. Series III, Leopold Stieglitz, consists of material concerning his life, including several journals from the 1880s. Series IV, Addition (1999) contains a group of lantern slides that copy earlier family photographs. Series V, Addition (2000) adds several letters, photographs and family items. Series VI, Addition (2005) contains five autochromes made by Nathan Straus Jr., with their diascope viewers; portraits include Flora Stieglitz Straus, her husband Hugh Grant Straus, and her maternal grandmother Jacobina Staerk Stieffel. Series VII, Addition (2008) includes correspondence, financial papers, photographs, diaries, and albums that document the friends, travels, and activities of the Stieglitz family in Europe and New York City, as well as at their summer home, Oaklawn, just north of the village of Lake George, New York.
Stieglitz family
Straus, Flora Stieglitz, 1895-1994
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The majority of the items in this collection were the bequest of the estate of Flora Stieglitz Straus. Other items were given by Stieglitz family members Sue Davidson Lowe and Elizabeth Davidson Murray. Much of the material concerning Leopold Stieglitz was collected by Robert Simpson and given to Flora Stieglitz Straus by Mrs. Simpson in 1972. Material in Series V was given by Sue Davidson Lowe in 1999 and added to the collection in 2000. The autochromes in Series VI were given by Ann Straus Gertler. Material in Series VII is from the estate of Flora Stieglitz Straus.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 10: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Folders 181-184 (Cold storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Alfred Stieglitz / Georgia O'Keeffe Archive (YCAL MSS 85)
STIEGLITZ FAMILY
Information about the Stieglitz family is readily available in many books about Alfred Stieglitz, including Sue Davidson Lowe's Stieglitz: A Memoir/Biography, which includes a detailed family tree that is very helpful in sorting out the photographer's extended family. The Flora Stieglitz Straus Collection contains a photocopy of a typescript draft of an autobiography by Edward J. Stieglitz ("Search for Maturity") that also includes biographical information about Julius Stieglitz. In addition, readers are directed to Herbert Newby McCoy's Julius Stieglitz, 1867-1937: A Biographical Sketch.
Scope and Contents
The Flora Stieglitz Straus Collection of Stieglitz Family Papers consist of letters, photographs, printed materials, journals, manuscripts, albums, and a scrapbook documenting the lives of many members of Alfred Stieglitz's extended family, in particular his father Edward and brothers Julius and Leopold, with some early correspondence to and from Stieglitz. The collection spans the years 1860-1999 and was accumulated mainly by Flora Stieglitz Straus (1895-1994), the niece of Alfred Stieglitz. Material in this collection complements other family papers found in Series XI of the Alfred Stieglitz/Georgia O'Keeffe Archive (YCAL MSS 85).
Included in the first series, Stieglitz Family Papers, are letters between family members, a draft of an autobiography by Edward J. Stieglitz, and biographical information about Julius Stieglitz. Series II, Alfred Stieglitz and Georgia O'Keeffe, contains a number of letters from Stieglitz and O'Keeffe to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson and Donald Douglas Davidson, and to Flora Stieglitz Straus. Series III, Leopold Stieglitz, consists of material concerning him and includes several of his journals from the 1880s. Series IV, Addition (1999), is a collection of lantern slides. Series V, Addition (2000), contains several letters, photographs and family items. Series VI, Addition (2005), consists of five autochrome portraits and their viewing devices. Series VII, Addition (2008), includes correspondence, financial papers, photographs, and albums that document the travels and activities of the Stieglitz family in Europe, New York City, and at their summer home, Oaklawn, just north of the village of Lake George, New York.
Because the material in this collection came from a number of family sources, the same types of documents (correspondence, invoices, photographs, etc.) will appear in many of the series.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into seven series: I. Stieglitz Family (1867-1990); II. Alfred Stieglitz and Georgia O'Keeffe (1880-1992); III. Leopold Stieglitz (1878-1954); IV. Addition (1999): Lantern Slides (circa 1920); V. Addition (2000): Correspondence, Photographs, Other Papers (1863-1999); VI. Addition (2005): Autochromes (circa 1915); VII. Addition (2008): Manuscripts, Photographs, Ephemera (1860-1945). Boxes 8, 9, and 18 contain Oversize items. Box 10 contains Restricted Fragile Papers for which preservation copies have been made.
Photographers -- United States; Lake George (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Albums (Books); Autochromes (photographs); Autograph albums; Cabinet photographs; Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Diaries; Diascopes; Drawings (visual works); Lantern slides; Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Theater programs -- Germany; Tintypes (prints); Photographers; De Casseres, Benjamin, 1873-1945; Ezekiel, Moses Jacob, 1844-1917; Hasemann, Wilhelm; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Stieffel, Jacobina Staerk; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946 -- Family; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946; Stieglitz, Edward J., 1899-1994; Stieglitz, Edward, 1833-1909; Stieglitz, Julius, 1867-1937; Stieglitz, Leopold; Straus, Flora Stieglitz, 1895-1994; Straus, Hugh Grant, 1890-1961; Straus, Nathan, 1889-1961; Stieglitz family -- Pictorial works; Stieglitz family
- Stieglitz Family, 1867-1990; Series I; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: Correspondence; Photographs; and Other Papers.
  Scope and Contents
  The series holds a variety of letters, photographs, and family papers. Correspondence contains letters between family members, which include several picture postcards collected by Sue Davidson Lowe. Photographs contains many portraits of family members, including the twin brothers Leopold and Julius Stieglitz, and images of Stieglitz family homes in Lake George and Mamaroneck, New York. [Copy negatives for several prints accompanied this collection. They are stored separately.] Among the Other Papers is the draft of an autobiography by gerontologist Edward J. Stieglitz ("Search for Maturity," which also contains biographical information about his father Julius Stieglitz), and a scrapbook kept by Elizabeth Stieffel Stieglitz.
  - Correspondence
    - Calderone, Mary Steichen to Leopold Stieglitz, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett, Mary to "Mrs. Stieglitz", 1905 Oct 14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rogers, Florence to "Mrs. Stieglitz", 1905 Sep 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Amy" to Leopold Stieglitz, 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stieglitz, Edward to Leopold Stieglitz, 1893 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Stieglitz, Edward to Selma Schubart, 1905 Aug 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Davidson, Elizabeth Stieglitz to Leopold Stieglitz, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Straus, Flora Stieglitz to Leopold Stieglitz, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Stieglitz, Hedwig to Jacobine Stieffel, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Stieglitz, Hedwig to Elizabeth Stieglitz, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Stieglitz, Hedwig to Flora Stieglitz Straus, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Stieglitz, Julius to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson, 1933 Jun 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Stieglitz, Julius to Leopold Stieglitz, 1903, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Stieglitz, Julius to "Lizzie", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Stieglitz, Katherine ("Kitty") to Flora and Elizabeth Stieglitz, 1909 Jul 21 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Stieglitz, Leopold to Edward Stieglitz, 1885 Oct 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stieglitz, Leopold to Elizabeth Stieffel Stieglitz, 1899-1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Lizzie" to "Amanda", 1902 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Stieglitz, Elizabeth Stieffel and daughter Elizabeth to Leopold Stieglitz, 1891, 1893, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Lizzie-Mother-Geggie" to Stieglitz family members, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Stieglitz, Hedwig to Leopold Stieglitz, 1892 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Mamele" to Leopold Stieglitz, 1892, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Unidentified to Leopold Stieglitz, 1892-1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Unidentified to "Lizzie", undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Photographs
    General note
    Many of the photographs are later (circa 1932) copy prints and not original to the dates shown
    - Elmcroft (Mamaroneck, NY), undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Cromwell, Georgia Engelhard, circa 1911 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Oaklawn, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Photograph album with prints of Stieglitz family members and famous works of art, undated
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, with brothers, sisters, and mother, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Stieglitz, Elizabeth Stieffel, 1889, circa 1932 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Stieglitz, Elizabeth and Flora, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Stieglitz, Hedwig, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
      [Photograph of a print by AS]
    - Stieglitz, Leopold, 1877-1927 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Includes tintype of Stieglitz with a violin; one print by Alfred Stieglitz.
    - Stieglitz, Leopold and Julius, circa 1875 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Stieglitz, Leopold, with grandchildren, 1915-1947 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Stieglitz, Leopold, in office with patients and secretary, circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "Dinner for Dr. Leopold Stieglitz tendered by his friends on his seventy-fifth birthday at the Lotos Club", 1942 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Another copy of this image (in Series V) is stored in box 18, folder 180
    - [Straus?], Hugh [Grant], in apartment with artworks, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Treutlein, Mrs. ("wife of Professor Treutlein"), undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified group of children, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified house [possibly on "The Hill" at Lake George] sent as Christmas greeting by Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Other Papers
    Arranged under three headings: Edward J. Stieglitz; Julius Stieglitz; and Other Family Members
    - Stieglitz, Edward J.
      - "Search For Maturity", [autobiography] typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 41-44)
        Includes a biography of his father, Julius Stieglitz
      - "Search For Maturity" [cont.], 1958 (Box 2, Folder 45-47)
      - Obituaries, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - "Report of a Survey of Active Studies in Gerontology", 1942 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Stieglitz, Julius
      - Clippings re: JS, 1917-1937 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Journal, [1882-1883] (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Julius Stieglitz Memorial Lecture by Dr. Schlesinger, typescript carbon, 1950 Apr 26 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Robert Simpson research correspondence re: JS, 1950, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Other family members
      - Obituary of Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson, with brochure for Hindu philosophy lecture, 1950 Apr (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Program (handmade) for performance of Pelleas et Millicent, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Scrapbook, 1922-1946 (Box 2, Folder 55-63)
        Kept by Elizabeth ("Geggie") Stieffel Stieglitz; contains clippings and programs about Alfred Stieglitz, Georgia O'Keeffe, and other Stieglitz family members.
- Alfred Stieglitz and Georgia O'Keeffe, 1880-1992; Series II; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  The series brings together materials documenting the life of the photographer and his second wife that were collected by several family members. Along with the clippings and exhibition catalogs are a number of runs of correspondence. These include letters from Alfred Stieglitz to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson and Donald Douglas Davidson, and to Elizabeth Stieffel Stieglitz, Leopold Stieglitz, and Flora Stieglitz Straus, as well as letters from Georgia O'Keeffe to Donald Douglas Davidson, to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson, and to Flora Stieglitz Straus. This series also contains a typescript carbon of an essay ("Joke") by Benjamin de Casseres written for "291" and a bookplate for Alfred Stieglitz most likely designed by Allen Lewis.
  Organized into five subseries: Correspondence; Clippings; Exhibition Catalogs; Printed Items; and Other Papers.
  - Correspondence
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia to Donald Douglas Davidson, 1924-1944 (Box 3, Folder 64)
      Includes: draft of letter from AS to [Mitchell] "Kenneled" on verso of letter of 1924
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson, 1917-1948, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia to Flora Stieglitz Straus, 1957-1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson and Donald Douglas Davidson, 1917-1931 (Box 3, Folder 67-76)
      Includes: Addendum by Georgia O'Keeffe on verso of letter of 1924 Nov 4
    - Stieglitz, Alfred to Elizabeth Stieffel Stieglitz, 1942-1946 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred to Leopold Stieglitz, 1880-1920 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred to Flora Stieglitz Straus, 1925-1943 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Strand, Rebecca to Elizabeth Stieglitz Davidson, 1923 Nov 5 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Letters to Flora Stieglitz Straus about Alfred Stieglitz, 1966-1989 (Box 3, Folder 81)
      Includes: letters from Laurie Lisle, Georgia O'Keeffe (photocopy of 1 letter), Diane Tucker, and Evan Turner; letter from FSS to "Ken"; and copy of letter from Dorothy Norman to Nan Talese
  - Clippings
    - About AS, 1934-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 82-83)
    - Offprint of article about AS from The New York Times, 1955 Dec 8 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - About exhibits of work by AS, 1934-1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Books about AS, 1977-1991 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - "Scenes from a Marriage" (excerpt from An American Romance by Benita Eisler), undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - About Georgia O'Keeffe, 1928-1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - About exhibits of work by Georgia O'Keeffe, 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Exhibition Catalogs
    - Alfred Stieglitz, 1896-1990 (Box 4, Folder 90-91)
    - Georgia O'Keeffe, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Arthur Dove, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - William Carlos Williams, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Intimate Gallery and Anderson Gallery shows, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 94)
      One signed by Stieglitz
  - Printed Items
    - An American Place publications: "To My Paint Children" by John Marin and "Prelude to a Church" by Dorothy Norman, 1937, undated (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Auction catalog pages listing Stieglitz prints, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Bookplate for Alfred Stieglitz [designed by Allen Lewis?], circa 1908 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Calendar with print of AS photograph: "The Terminal", 1979
    - MSS, numbers 2, 3, and 4, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Program: Dedication of Stieglitz Hall, City College of New York, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Other Papers
    - "Alfred Stieglitz (1864-1946)" by Dorothy Norman, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - "Joke" by Benjamin de Casseres, typescript carbon [written for "291"], undated (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - List of works and printed items re: AS, 1968, 1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Notes on AS by Flora Stieglitz Straus, 1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Photographs - Contact sheet prints of works by AS and others, undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
- Leopold Stieglitz, 1878-1954; Series III; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  The series contains papers related to Alfred Stieglitz's younger brother Leopold, who gained renown as a physician. The first subseries contains routine personal and professional Correspondence. The second subseries, Writings, consists of items on medical topics along with stories and plays. Among the Personal Papers are several volumes of journals that cover Stieglitz's school days in Germany during the 1880s, and his diplomas and awards.
  Organized into three subseries: Correspondence; Writings; and Personal Papers.
  - Correspondence
    - A - E, general, 1892-1952 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - [Everard, Natalie?], undated (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - F - J general, 1892-1950 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Heltzel, William, from Leopold Stieglitz, 1905 Dec 3 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - K - O, general, 1913-1952 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - P - S, general, 1942-1952 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - W and Z, general, 1892-1952 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Unidentified, 1917-1952 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Professional (medical) correspondence, 1892-1935 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Letters re: Lotos Club birthday dinner, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Writings
    - Medical writings by LS, printed versions, 1893-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - List of medical writings by LS, undated (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - [Statement on why he became a doctor], typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Stories and plays by LS, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 118-122)
  - Personal Papers
    - Change of address card, undated (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Clippings re: LS, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Clippings showing crowds on New York City streets (with LS in automobile?), 1909-1910 (Box 5, Folder 125)
      Includes: photographic enlargement of one scene
    - Diplomas and awards, 1878-1912
      Includes: medical degree from the University Ruperto-Carola (1891); attendance awards from the Grammar School for Boys (1878-1879); declaration of election as Fellow of the New York Academy of Medicine (1912)
    - Journal, [1881-1882] (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Journals, [1882-1884] (Box 6, Folder 127-131)
    - Leopold Stieglitz Visiting Professorship lectures - programs and text, 1949-1954 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Offprint from The Musician: "This Rotary Business", 1929 Oct (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Physician's Visiting Lists, 1896, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 134-135)
    - Publication: "Education in New York State: 1784-1954" featuring photograph of LS's medical license (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Publication: "The Story of Lenox Hill Hospital", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Student Identification card, 1887 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Telephone list, undated (Box 7, Folder 139)
- Addition (1999): Lantern Slides, circa 1920; Series IV; 0.25; (1 box)
  The series contains a group of lantern slides that copy earlier family photographs. Descriptions of the images were taken from a list provided by Sue Davidson Lowe; according to a note accompanying the material, Flora Straus recalled in 1986 that the slides were probably made for her by Alfred Stieglitz, and were shown at a family New Years Eve celebration in the early 1920s.
  Organized into three subseries: By Leopold Stieglitz; By Leopold or Julius Stieglitz; and Studio Photographs, Groups and Portraits.
  - By Leopold Stieglitz
    - Daughter Flora at table with book, [1905?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 149)
    - Daughter Elizabeth at beach, [1905?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - Daughter Flora (oval portrait), circa 1908-1909, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 151)
    - Group at Lake George (including Lizzie and Elizabeth), circa 1915-1916, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - By Leopold or Julius Stieglitz
    - Elizabeth, Flora, unidentified boy, ____ Morris, at "teepee," [1908?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - Flora, Hedwig, and Elizabeth with tennis racquets, [1910?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 154)
  - Studio photos, groups & portraits
    - Hedwig with infant twin sons in plaid dresses, circa 1867, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 155)
    - Alfred Stieglitz's toy horses, circa 1873-1875, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 156)
    - Edward, Hedwig, Rosa, and others in rowboat on Lake George, [1874?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 157)
    - Edward and Alfred Stieglitz with bow and arrow, Lake George, circa 1875-1878, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 158)
    - Selma and Agnes Stieglitz playing cards with Eugene Small at Lake George, circa 1876-1877, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 159)
    - Photo portrait of Hedwig by Encke, circa 1877-1879, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 160)
    - Photo portrait of Edward by Kurtz studio, 1881 May 16, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 161)
    - Agnes seated beside table, circa 1881-1882, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 162)
    - Lizzie, [1887?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 163)
    - Selma with infant Howard, circa 1892-1893, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 164)
    - Agnes seated at table, circa 1892-1893, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Lizzie with infant [Flora or Elizabeth], [1897?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - Lizzie with Flora and Elizabeth, 1897, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - G. H. Engelhard, [1898?], circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 168)
    - Stearns, Katherine ("Kitty") Stieglitz, Stuttgart, 1904, circa 1920 (Box 11, Folder 169)
- Addition (2000): Correspondence, Photographs, Other Papers, 1863-1999; Series V; 0.21; (1 box)
  The series contains items such as letters from Katherine ("Kitty") Stieglitz Stearns to Flora Stieglitz Straus, a script for a skit done at Lake George, and photographs of Leopold Stieglitz and Flora Straus.
  - Correspondence
    - Schubart, Selma to Howard Schubart, 1908 Aug 23 (Box 12, Folder 170)
    - Schubart, Selma to Elizabeth Stieglitz, 1904 Oct 25 (Box 12, Folder 171)
    - Stearns, Katherine ("Kitty") Stieglitz, to Flora Stieglitz Straus, 1907, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 172)
    - Unidentified to Hedwig Stieglitz, 1906 Mar (Box 12, Folder 173)
  - Photographs
    - Stearns, Katherine ("Kitty") Stieglitz, circa 1921 (Box 12, Folder 174)
    - Stieglitz, Leopold or Julius [or both?], undated (Box 12, Folder 175)
      Two cartes-de-visite in tooled leather case, with dried flower
    - "Dinner for Dr. Leopold Stieglitz tendered by his friends on his seventy-fifth birthday at the Lotos Club", 1942 May 26
      Another copy of this image is in Series I, box 1, folder 36
  - Other Papers
    - "The Oaklawn Follies of 1919," script for skit at Lake George, typescript corrected, photocopy, circa 1919 (Box 12, Folder 176)
      Includes notes by Flora Stieglitz Straus and Sue Davidson Lowe
    - Howard Schubart's notes for Stieglitz cousins' production of Tannhauser at Lake George, concerning puppet costumes, circa 1910 (Box 12, Folder 177)
    - Bills addressed to Edward Stieglitz, 1863-1883 (Box 12, Folder 178)
      Concerning: home improvements; cigars; wine; and English lessons
    - Notes by Sue Davidson Lowe accompanying Series IV additions, circa 1999 (Box 12, Folder 179)
- Addition (2005): Autochromes, 1915; Series VI; 0.63; (2 boxes)